viralglobalnews.com 2015-09-10

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

Thank you for visiting www.viralglobalnews.com, a site presented to you by Virtual Solutions Center, Inc. Your privacy is incredibly important to Viral Global News. As a result, we provide this Privacy Policy to explain our commitment to keeping your personal privacy information secure. This Privacy Policy also explains our online information practices and the choices available to users navigating our site.

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Viral Global News collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the [www.viralglobalnews.com](http://www.viralglobalnews.com/ "Viral Global News \(VGN\)") website (“Site”). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Viral Global News.

## Personally identifiable information

We may collect personally identifiable information from Users in a variety of ways, relating to activities, services, features or resources we make available on the Site. In some regions of the Site, users may be able to enter competitions, vote in polls or otherwise express an opinion, subscribe to the Viral Global News online newsletter, or participate in our online communities and leave comments.

The type of personally identifiable information collected depends upon the specific services, features and resources the User is accessing and/or using. Examples of personal information we sometimes seek to collect from you, at these posts and pages, includes User names, e-mail addresses and website names. However, users may visit our Site anonymously, if they so wish. We will only collect personally identifiable information from Users if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identifiable information, although it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site-related activities.

You may also have the opportunity to engage with our content through third-party social networking sites, such as Facebook and Twitter, or third-party social media applications and plugin-ins. When Users engage with Viral Global News’ content through third-party social networking sites, plug-ins or applications, you may provide us with access to select information from your social media profile to deliver the content, or as part of the application or plugin-in’s regular operation; this includes, but is not limited to, your name, e-mail address, avatar, gender, location, birthday and friends list.

Some social networking sites allow users to adjust their platform’s privacy settings, according to user preference. For more information on controlling how social networking sites handle your personal information, please refer to their site-specific terms of use and privacy policies.

## Non-personally identifiable information

We, our third-party service providers, advertisers, agencies and partners may collect non-personally identifiable information about Users whenever they interact with the Site. Non-personally identifiable information collected may include, but is not limited to, the browser name (e.g. Google Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g. Microsoft Windows, Mac OS), the domain name of your Internet service provider, or ISP, (e.g. AT&T, Verizon), the Site pages you have visited, location information, the content and advertisements you have accessed, seen or clicked on, and the type of mobile device used to view the Site (e.g. iPhone, HTC).

When engaging in Viral Global News content delivered through third-party social networking sites, or third-party social media applications and plug-ins, we may also obtain non-personally identifiable information from the User’s interaction with our content. This may include, but is not limited to, advertisement information within content you have disseminated or clicked on.

Some social networking sites allow users to adjust their platform’s privacy settings, according to user preference. For more information on controlling how social networking sites handle your personal information, please refer to their site-specific terms of use and privacy policies.

## Web browser cookies and web beacons

Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. The User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Cookies are text files that are often placed in the User’s computer browser to store preferences. Although cookies don’t store personally identifiable information, once a User provides a website personally identifiable information, such information may be linked to the data stored inside a cookie text file.

We use cookies to understand the Site’s usage and to improve the content, services and advertisements on the Site. We may use this information to personalize User experience and to help us offer relevant advertising. These cookies may also be used by us, our third-party service providers, advertisers, agencies and partners to gauge performance of displayed advertisements, delivered on the Site.

Users may choose to set their web browser to refuse all cookies, refuse certain cookies, accept all cookies, or to ensure cookies are only accepted upon the User’s consent. If you choose to do so, please note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

We, our third-party service providers, advertisers, agencies or partners may also use web beacons, or similar technologies, to collect information about the visitors that view a particular page ad monitor behavior. For example, these web beacons may be utilized to deliver cookies to Users’ browsers visiting the Site, or to count the number of Users visiting a particular web page or post.

## How we use collected information

Viral Global News may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:

  * _– To personalize user experience_  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users, as a group, use the services and resources provided on the Site.
  * _– To improve the Site_  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services, including the design of the website
  * _– To send periodic emails_  
We may use email addresses provided by Users to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other submitted requests.
  * – _To send periodic newsletters_  
We may use email addresses provided by Users to send newsletters to those individuals who have signed up to the Viral Global News online newsletter
  * – _To enforce the legal terms that govern your use of the Site_

If you elect to [submit news tips, content for publication](http://www.viralglobalnews.com/submissions/ "User submissions and Contact Us") or engage in discussions in the Site’s comments section, we may publish your screen name and other information you have provided to Viral Global News. Any comments, photos or videos that you include in the Site comments sections will be displayed publicly on the Viral Global News website and may be reused and redistributed by us, at our discretion.

When the User provides information from their social networking account or profile, it can help us provide the User with exclusive content and make contact with them through specific social networking platforms. When the User provides such information, it also allows them to share Viral Global News content and experiences via social networking platforms. When you provide Viral Global News with personal information through applications, plug-ins and social networking sites, you agree it may be publicly viewed by other members of the Site and we are unable to prevent third-parties from using this information.

## How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, and other such User-specific data stored on the Site.

Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures.

## Sharing your personal information

Viral Global News may share generic, demographic information, not linked to any personally identifiable information, regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We do not sell, trade, or rent Users’ personally identifiable information to third-parties.

We may provide personally identifiable information in response to legal process; for example, personally identifiable information may be disclosed by Viral Global News in response to a court order or subpoena. We may also disclose personally identifiable information in response to a request from law enforcement agencies, or where we deem it necessary to investigate and safeguard against illegal activities, cases of suspected fraud and reports of threats to another individual’s physical well-being.

We may also disclose personally identifiable information in the event our terms of use are violated, and to enforce compliance with laws and policies that govern the Site. In addition, we may also share personally identifiable information in the event that we are acquired by, sold to, merged or otherwise moved to another entity.

Our agents, contributors and contractors who are provided access to such personally identifiable information are required to ensure this information is protected, in accordance with the terms outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Although Viral Global News takes precautions to protect the privacy and personally identifiable information of our users, we are unable to guarantee the information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

## Advertising

Ads appearing on our site may be delivered to Users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non-personally identifiable information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Google Adsense

Some of the ads may be served by Google. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Users, based on their visit to the Site and other sites on the Internet. DART uses “non personally identifiable information” and does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, etc. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy, at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/>

## Changes to this privacy policy

Viral Global News has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how Viral Global News is helping protect the personal information it collects. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and ensure you remain aware of modifications.

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of Viral Global News’ Privacy Policy and [Terms and Conditions](http://www.viralglobalnews.com/terms-conditions/ "VGN Terms and Conditions"). If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the Site. Your continued use of the Site, following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

## Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Site, or your dealings with the Site, please contact us at the following address:

Virtual Solutions Center, Inc.  
Attention: Privacy  
25016 Mill River Road,  
Olmsted Falls, Ohio 44138

Users can also contact us, via telephone, on 440-822-1758, or at the following e-mail address: editor@viralglobalnews.com

Further contact information can be found in the [Contact Us section of the Site](http://www.viralglobalnews.com/submissions/ "Contact Us").

This document was last updated on July 21, 2015.
